NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
I've realized something.
（アイコ）私 思ったの
Until now, Kanzaki,
you've lied about many things.
神崎(かんざき)君は今まで
たくさんのウソをついてきた
About my body and my mind.
この体のこと 脳のこと
ダイバーのみんなにも
隠し事をしてた
You've hidden things from the Divers.
You probably have many other secrets, too.
多分 ほかにも たくさん
（雄哉(ゆうや)）それは…
But that's...
I was made from your lies.
（アイコ）
私は あなたのウソで出来ている
あっ…
〜
I was made from your lies.
私は あなたのウソで出来ている
あっ…
Even though my brain
is fake and artificial,
でもね
この脳が偽物でも作り物でも
I still love Mom and Ryota.
私は お母さんと亮太(りょうた)を愛してる
These feelings are not fake.
この気持ちは偽物なんかじゃない
I want to save them both.
２人を助けたい
I want to return this body
to the other me.
もう１人の私に この体を返したい
She intends to sacrifice her own life
to put an end to all this.
彼女は自分の命と引き換えに
すべてを終わらせる気でいる
But that is my role.
でも それは私の役目
橘(たちばな)
Tachibana.
That is not my name.
それは私の名前じゃない
There is only one Aiko Tachibana.
橘アイコは１人でいいの
（雄哉）
君は… 君はそれでいいのか？
Are you sure you want to do this?
Why are you asking?
Isn't that what you want?
（アイコ）
どうして？
それがあなたの望みなんでしょ
If we don't hurry, the other me--
早くしないと もう１人の私が…
Hold on! I--
（雄哉）待ってくれ 僕は
（アイコ）神崎君
-Kanzaki--
-No!
違う！
あっ…
I'm not Yuya Kanzaki, either.
僕もまた 神崎雄哉じゃない
Okay, let's begin.
（伊佐津(いさづ)）さあ 始めようか
（竹原(たけはら)）待ってください
Hold on!
Please don't interfere.
邪魔をしないでくれないか
Sir!
先生！
Dr. Isazu.
（佐保(さほ)）伊佐津先生
（竹原）あっ…
佐保君？
Saho?
Is it really okay to do this, sir?
（佐保）
先生 本当に大丈夫ですか？
こんなことをなさって
It's been proven
we can establish a link.
（伊佐津）
リンクが張れることは実証済みだ
And...
それに
Yuzuha is my daughter.
柚葉(ゆずは)は私の娘だよ
Yuzuha?
（竹原）柚葉ちゃん？
Saho, did you know about this?
おい 佐保君
君は何か知ってるのか？
ええ もちろん
Yes, of course.
I've been with Yuzuha and Dr. Isazu
for a long time, you know.
私は ずっと柚葉ちゃんと
伊佐津先生のおそばに
おりましたから
あっ…
It's only natural that I assist
in restoring Yuzuha's consciousness.
すべては柚葉ちゃんが目覚めるため
お手伝いは当然です
（伊佐津）うっ うう…
Okay, Yuzuha. Lend me your strength.
さあ 柚葉
私に力を貸しておくれ
うっ！ くっ！
うう…
I believed that my body and my life
would last only until...
（雄哉）
僕の この体 この命は
バーストを終息させるまでのもの
the Burst is ended.
そう思っていた
あっ…
But, not you. You're...
でも君はそうじゃない
もう…
（メキメキメキ…）
（２人）あっ…
（２人）はっ…
（２人）あっ…うっ
（２人）あっ…えっ？
Aiko.
（伊佐津）アイコ君
（２人）あっ…
What?
（黒瀬(くろせ)）なに！
There's no need to sacrifice yourself.
（伊佐津）
君が犠牲になる必要はないんだよ
You are undoubtedly one of a kind.
君は れっきとした１人の人間
Dr. Isazu?
（小春(こはる)）伊佐津博士？
Is he controlling the Matter?
ヤツがマターを操ってるってのか
There's no reason for you
to get caught up in his obsession
その男の妄執に巻き込まれ
人の姿を失うことなどない
and lose your life.
（２人）うっ
I can put your life to much better use.
私なら もっときちんと
君の命を使ってあげられる
（雄哉）うわっ
Kanzaki!
（アイコ）神崎君！
神崎君！
くっ！
This Matter is from the duplicate bodies
（伊佐津）
このマターたちは貴様の作品である
you created using Cell Assembler Two.
セル･アセンブラ２によって
作られた複製体
They just don't have functioning brains.
ただ脳が機能できなかっただけ
They're all my daughter.
すべて私の娘だ
Even now, their minds are connected
to my comatose daughter.
今も眠ったままの柚葉の心と
つながっている
To return Yuzuha to consciousness,
柚葉が真に目覚めるためには
Aiko Tachibana,
橘アイコ君
I must have
your artificial organism brain.
君の人工生体脳が
どうしても必要なのだ
My brain?
（アイコ）わ… 私の？
You see,
（伊佐津）
そうとも
the only brain ever regenerated,
脳神経組織の再生
or should I say,
the only successfully created brain...
いや 新生に成功した ただ一つの例
is yours.
それが君だ
I will probe your brain at the
molecular level to discover its secret.
君の脳を分子レベルまで
かき分けて
私は その秘密を突き止める
あっ…
This is insane!
なんてこと
由良(ゆら)と伊佐津は 今まで
あの子の脳みそを奪い合って
So, Yura and Isazu
have been fighting to get her brain?
So it seems.
そう… なるな
You monsters! Grown men
fighting over a young girl's brain?
バカなの！
あんな女の子に いい大人が
あっ…
You succeeded in bringing to life
（伊佐津）
史上初めて実用化された人工生体脳
an artificial organism brain
for the first time in history.
それは今まで その可能性だけが
一人歩きしてきた
由良ノートの成果
違うか？
Is this all recorded in the Yura Notes?
くっ
Tell me! What is the secret?
（伊佐津）
言え！ その正体は何だ？
（アイコ）いやあ！
（雄哉）あっ…
ぐっ…
あ…
Tachibana!
（雄哉）橘！
I won't kill her.
I don't want her to hear this.
（伊佐津）
殺しはしない
彼女に聞かせたい話でもないだろう
All right, tell me!
さあ 答えろ
It's Cell Assembler...
セル･アセンブラ
Three.
３だ
What? Three?
ああ？ ３だ？
Impossible!
バカな
You mean you upgraded the Cell Assembler?
セル･アセンブラが
アップデートされていただと？
Thanks to Cell Assembler Two,
セル･アセンブラ２によって
resilient cells were able to
reproduce rapidly.
迅速かつ強靭(きょうじん)な
再生能力を得た細胞は
They couldn't be damaged or degraded.
傷つくことも老いることもない
But, that wasn't enough to make a brain.
でも それだけじゃ
脳を作ることはできなかった
A brain develops
脳の発達は
by eliminating
previously established connections.
すでに あるつながりが
消えることによって起こる
Early on in development,
randomly created connections
発達の初期段階で
無作為に生じたつながりは
are soon selectively destroyed,
やがて選択的に消滅し
and a refined network grows.
洗練されたネットワークへと
成長していく
I know that!
（伊佐津）
そんなことは分かっている
Theoretically, artificial reproduction
of a human personality
だが その過程は
高い不確定性に支配される
capable of controlling
such a highly uncertain process--
特定の人格の完全複製など
原理的に…
（雄哉）不可能だった
（伊佐津）うっ…
Was impossible.
Therefore,
だから僕は
after I accelerated network creation
to be as fast as possible,
ネットワークの形成速度を
極限まで高めたあと
I waited...
待った
うっ…
until the person
called Aiko Tachibana emerged.
（雄哉）橘アイコと呼べるものが
そこに出現するまで
Impossible!
（伊佐津）
ありえない！
That would take as long
as the evolution of life itself!
それでは生命の進化と
同じ時間がかかってしまう
As I developed Cell Assembler Two,
（雄哉）
だからこそ僕は
セル･アセンブラ２と並行して
ドリームコンタクトの技術を
開発した
I also developed Dream Contact technology.
Dream Contact?
（伊佐津）
ドリームコンタクト
Like you said,
（雄哉）あなたの言うとおり
脳の形成は
生命進化の過程とよく似ている
brain formation resembles
the evolution of life.
自然選択に任せれば
To proceed naturally,
任意の状態の脳の複製には
無限に等しいプロセスが必要だ
an emulation of
infinite possibilities is needed
to duplicate a mind
with a will of its own.
けれど オリジナルの
橘アイコの脳活性状態は
I was able to perfectly monitor
the brain activity
of the original Aiko Tachibana.
完璧にモニター できていた
The goal was in sight.
ゴールは見えていたんだ
I repeatedly did the reverse calculations.
だから僕は
そこから逆算した結果を重ねた
All the unlimited divergent possibilities
cancelled each other out and optimized.
無限に発散するはずの可能性は
互いに打ち消し合い 最適化され
In a surprisingly short time,
驚くほど短時間で
an artificial brain that could be called
Aiko Tachibana came into existence.
人工生体脳は
橘アイコという状態へと収束した
あんたの相棒
ちょっと魔物じみてる
Your friend is a bit of a mad scientist.
That mad scientist is our only hope now.
今はその魔物だけが希望だ
バースト終息の可能性は まだ…
He can still stop the Burst.
（アラーム）
（２人）あっ…
As I'm sure you can see,
（アナウンサー）
ご覧いただけますでしょうか
マリグナント･エリア焼灼(しょうしゃく)に向け
the reinforcements at Camp Toyama
are leaving the base, and heading out
to incinerate the Malignant Matter Area.
ここ富山駐屯地に集結していた
増派部隊も次々と出発していきます
All Self-Defense Forces branches
are being concentrated
政府は陸海空自衛隊の総力を結集し
for a decisive strike
to end the crisis.
一気に事態の収束を図る構えです
MALIGNANT AREA
TO BE INCINERATED
あ…
あああああ！
Fine!
I acknowledge your godlike abilities!
お前の手は神の手だ！
認めよう
だが それをあるべきところへ返せ
But things must return
to where they belong!
Return gods to the gods!
Return Yuzuha to me!
神の手は神に！
柚葉は私に！
Back to the gods with you, Toshihide Yura!
神の御許へゆけよ
由良俊英(としひで)！
Know Yuzuha's pain!
柚葉の苦しみを知れ！
Be punished for preventing
her from waking up!
目覚めを妨げた報いを受けろ！
あっ！
（アイコ）はっ…
（グミ）キュイ
Gummi?
グミ？
Where am I?
ここは どこ？
Is this the other me?
もう１人の私の…
（すすり泣き）
Who's that?
（アイコ）誰？
A girl?
女の子？
Which body should I go back to?
（柚葉）どの体に戻ればいいの？
Why is she crying?
（アイコ）何？ 何を泣いてるの？
I want to get out of here. Tell me how.
（柚葉）教えて ここから出たいの
Stop it, Dad. Don't hurt Dr. Yura.
お父さん やめて
由良先生を…
あっ…
Yura? Hey! Wait!
由良？ ねえ 待って！
Please don't hurt him.
（柚葉）お願い 先生を
Hey, wait! What's happening to Kanzaki?
ねえ 待って！
神崎君がどうしたの？
（柚葉）殺さないで！
Don't kill him!
うっ！
（一樹(かずき)）
アイコちゃん アイコちゃん！
Aiko! Aiko!
Kazuki.
一樹君
（一樹）よかった　はっ！
Thank goodness.
-Kanzaki!
-This way! Hurry!
（一樹）神崎！
（雄哉）こっちだ 早く！
Kanzaki.
（アイコ）神崎君
I'm going to jump, Aiko.
（一樹）飛ぶよ アイコちゃん
（アイコ）え？
I'll take a magazine.
（雄哉）マガジン もらう
この階段を下るんだ
Take these stairs.
早く！
Hurry!
The Self-Defense Forces will attack soon.
（伊佐津）
自衛隊が総攻撃の準備に入った
There's no way you can accomplish
what you came to do, Yura.
由良 貴様の目的は
もう果たされることはない
Give it all up! Get in the shelter!
すべてを中止し シェルターに入れ
Obey me!
私に従え！
Director!
（堀(ほり)）局長！
All AMBREC companies
announced they'll cancel
アメビレック関連企業が
足並み そろえて
知財権の独占提供を打ち切ると
our exclusive use
of their technologies.
総攻撃になれば
最先端技術が ごっそり国外に
If the attack proceeds,
all that science will go abroad.
-Not yet.
-What?
（南原(なんばら)）まだよ
え？
We can stall this a little bit longer.
まだ少しは時間を稼げるはず
Hori.
堀君
Yes?
はい
I have a favor to ask you.
あなたにお願いがあるの
（アイコ）きゃあ！
Damn it!
（雄哉）しまった！
（２人）え？
はっ　これって…
This must be...
I'll try to suppress the Matter.
（橘アイコ）
私がマターの体を押さえこんでみる
She's protecting us.
守ってくれてるんだ
Protecting us?
守って？
Okay, let's go!
（一樹）よし 行くよ
（アイコ）え？
（アイコ）うわっ
（雄哉）ぐは…
（２人）え？
Is Tachibana okay?
（雄哉）橘は無事か？
Is she all right?
無事なんだな？
-Yes, she's fine!
-Kanzaki!
（一樹）ああ 大丈夫だ
（アイコ）神崎君！
（雄哉）
右に折れた突き当たりの部屋へ！
僕もすぐに行く
Turn right. It's the last room!
I'll be there soon!
I will protect...
僕が橘アイコを
Tachibana Aiko!
守る！
（荒い息）
Kanzaki!
（アイコ）神崎君！
（一樹）神崎！
（一樹）ハア…
This isn't the shelter, is it?
シェルターじゃないよな？
It's a medicinal warehouse.
（雄哉）薬剤保管庫
It's pretty sturdy.
多少は頑丈だ
Kanzaki, I saw a girl inside the Matter.
神崎君 私 マターの中で
女の子を見たの
女の子？
A girl?
She was a pretty girl with long hair.
髪の長い きれいな子
“ここから出して”
She wanted to get out,
and asked which body to go back to.
“どの体に戻ればいいの？”って
あっ…
Where should I go?
（柚葉）
私は どこに行けばいいの？
So, that's what's going on.
そういうことか
Hey, what are you doing? What's your plan?
（一樹）
おい 何してんだ
どうする気だよ
Let's go, Aiko. Let's get to the shelter.
アイコちゃん 行こう
シェルターに避難するんだ
Aiko!
アイコちゃん！
I'm sorry, but I'm not going.
（アイコ）
ごめんなさい　私 行けない
Why not? I don't want you to die!
どうして？
俺は君を死なせたくないんだ
Before I met you,
when my arm was grabbed by the Matter...
君と出会う前
俺はマターに腕をつかまれて
I saw a vision.
幻を見た
はっ
はっ！
There was a happy family.
A traffic accident. The Burst.
幸せそうな家族
交通事故 バースト
I understand it now.
今なら分かる
Those were your memories!
あれは君の記憶なんだ
I want to save you!
俺は君を救いたい
No matter how hard things get,
君がどんなにつらくても
I swear I'll be by your side!
俺が絶対 一緒にいる！
Kazuki, that was not me.
一樹君 それは私じゃない
It's memories of the other me.
もう１人の私の記憶
What?
え？
That wasn't me.
それは私じゃないの
あっ　くっ
I can't understand it! How can that be?
分かんないよ どうして
I love...
俺は君が…
I'm in love with you!
俺が好きなのは 君なんだ
Thank you, but...
ありがとう　でも…
Don't say it!
（一樹）言うなよ！
Give me your gun.
（雄哉）銃を貸してくれ
（一樹）ハア
This will cause an explosion
when ignited.
（雄哉）着火すれば
爆発的燃焼を起こす
ドアと外のマターを吹き飛ばして
道を開く
It'll blow a path
through the door and the Matter.
Are you crazy?
ふざけんな！
Fine. Shoot it, then.
（雄哉）
そうか　なら 君が撃ってくれ
Get down as soon as you pull the trigger.
引き金を引いたら
すぐに体を伏せるんだ
神崎！
Kanzaki!
俺には分かる
I can sense it!
お前だって アイコちゃんのこと
何とも思ってないわけがない
I know you have feelings for Aiko, too!
それでも行くのかよ
But you'll still do it?
それでもアイコちゃんに
マターになれって言うのかよ！
You still plan on turning her
into the Matter?
Will you toss her aside
and tell her to die?
人を捨てて
消えろって言うのかよ！
Kazuki.
一樹君
私のことを思ってくれるなら
どうか救ってください
If you love me, then save them.
Aiko.
（一樹）アイコちゃん
Not my body or my mind.
この体でも 脳でもない
お母さんと亮太を助けたい
Save my Mom and Ryota.
My heart demands it!
そう叫び続けてる この心を！
あっ…
うおおおお！
Tank and artillery battalions will
commence firing at 8:00 p.m. as planned.
（第三部長）
戦車大隊 特科大隊 予定どおり
２０:００(フタマルマルマル)時より射撃を開始します
（第二部長）
エリア内に民間人の侵入者 多数
There are numerous
civilian trespassers in the Area.
All units, hold your fire!
（師団長）各部隊 射撃待て
You really are amazing.
あなたって人は…
Explain yourself, Nanbara!
（大臣）説明しろ 南原
I exercised my right as Director
to lift the Malignant Area blockade.
局長権限で
マリグナント･エリアの封鎖を
解除しました
何のつもりか！
For what reason?!
Since Matter activity
in Area Four has ceased,
エリア４までのマターが
不活性した現在
I decided that securing samples
there took priority.
サンプル保全作業を
優先すべきと判断しました
くっ… 貴様
Damn you!
エリア内の対処は
一任を受けたはずですが
I was given
complete authority over the Area.
ふざけるな！
ダイバーどもは撤収
That's enough!
Recall those Divers!
You're relieved of your post immediately!
貴様は この場で解任 更迭だ！
If you don't want to go down with her,
tell me everything she knows!
共倒れが嫌なら
あの女の握っていたものを
すべて吐き出せ
Write a report immediately!
報告をまとめてこい
Hello? Who is this?
（黒瀬）はい どなた？
Nanbara asked me to call.
My name is Hori. I work for her.
（堀）
南原の指示でご連絡しました
部下の堀と申します
You work for her?
南原の？
I have a message.
（堀）
用件だけ
The attack on the Area has been postponed.
エリアへの総攻撃は 一時中止です
Really?
なんだって？
The Director has bought you time.
（堀）
局長が時間を稼ぎました
そうか あいつはどうしてる？
I see. What happened to her?
She has sacrificed everything
she worked for, her entire career,
（堀）
あの人はご自分のすべてともいえる
キャリアと引き換えに
to stop the attack.
攻撃を止めてみせた
What? Don't tell me...
お… おい まさか！
She constantly spoke about
the interests of the nation.
（堀）
二言目には 国益 国益と
うるさい人でしたが
I've never seen anyone sacrifice
so much for something
そんな不確かなものに
あそこまで殉じられる人を
僕は知らない
so abstract.
The attack would only make
the Burst worse.
総攻撃は むしろ
バーストを悪化させるだけだ
Your boss did the right thing.
あんたのボスは正しかった
She'll be rewarded.
（堀）
報われます
The attack has been postponed.
Inform Yura.
攻撃は中止だ
由良に知らせてくれ
Impossible.
無理でしょ
We can see Research Facility Two.
第二研内部のモニターは
できてるけど
But if we contact them,
Isazu will find out, too.
（黒瀬）
こっちから呼びかけたら
伊佐津にも知られちまうってことか
そうか
I know!
ん？
What's that?
何だ？
Is it broken?
（雄哉）故障？
-It's saying something.
-What?
（一樹）何か しゃべってる
（雄哉）え？
"Yuya, come in."
（一樹）“雄哉 応答せよ”
（アイコ）え？
Kurose?
（雄哉）黒瀬さん
Visible light communication?
可視光通信か
We got through!
通じたのか
He's answering!
返信だ
I'll read it.
読むわ
“柚葉ちゃんと彼女の複製体との
リンクを切れ”
"Cut the link between Yuzuha
and her duplicate bodies."
What?
なに？
Link?
リンク？
The comatose girl
is linked to her duplicate bodies?
意識不明の子と複製体が
つながってるってこと？
Isazu is trying to return Yuzuha
to consciousness.
伊佐津が柚葉ちゃんの意識を
取り戻そうとして
He's trying to physically sync
her with her duplicate bodies' brains.
彼女の複製体の脳と
物理的に同期を図ろうとしたんだ
１つも成功しなかったのに
そんなもん まだつなげてたのか！
None of them succeeded.
So why were they still connected?
（小春）
じゃあ リンクを切るってのは？
Then, how do we cut the link?
桐生(きりゅう)病院
At Kiryu Hospital.
It means we sneak in
right under Isazu's nose.
伊佐津のお膝元に
潜り込めってことだ
Three blocks to Primary Point.
（白石(しらいし)）
プライマリー･ポイントまで
３ブロック
But no sign of
the two people we need.
（遙香(はるか)）
でも肝心の２人が見当たらない
-Seri!
-Damn!
（白石）芹(せり)さん！
（遙香）しまった！
（２人）え？
Kaede!
（遙香）楓(かえで)！
（楓）ヘヘッ
あいつらが迷子になってんなら
If they're lost...
Then we'll just have to bring them
to their objective.
（相模(さがみ)）
俺たちが目的地から
出迎えに行ってやろうじゃねえか
There's a purpose to what we're doing.
この道行きに意味はある
（２人）あっ…
Right!
ええ
RECALL THE SELF-DEFENSE FORCES!
（堀）
御社をはじめとする
アメビレックの存続こそ
The existence of your company
and AMBREC itself
is in the national interest.
国益そのものです
希望はまだあります
There is still hope.
（伊佐津）由良…
Yura...
由良〜！
Yura!
Stop it!
もう やめてください
Don't interfere, Takehara!
竹原さん 邪魔をしないでください
This is an official operation!
これは正式なオペなんですよ
あ…
This is Primary Point.
（雄哉）
ここがプライマリー･ポイントだ
（アイコ）え？
（一樹）ここが？
-What?
-Here?
The multipurpose surgical installation
ALSUS is in here.
（雄哉）
多目的手術装置アルサスは
この中にある
行こう
Let's go.
I know this place.
（アイコ）ここは… 私 知ってる
I've seen it many times
in my dreams.
何度も夢に出てきた場所だ
（雄哉）あ…
（一樹･アイコ）あっ
This is ALSUS?
（一樹）これがアルサス？
〜
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey